today I'm a seven figure Trader where I
make anywhere from $50 to $100,000 every
single day with realistically about 1 or
2 hours a day that I look at the charts
but it really wasn't always like this it
took me about 2 and 1/2 years to make
any money in the market let alone be a
consistently profitable Trader plus tens
of thousand dollars and endless hours in
front of a chart trying to figure out
the secret behind how to become a
profitable Trader and how to live this
crazy lifestyle and even though in the
industry it's often to say that about
80% is psychology and 20% is technical I
totally agree but for me personally what
actually changed my approach to the
market and was able to let me scale was
risk management it's cool once you
understand psychology you figure out the
trading but without having that 20% of
Technical and risk management simply
won't be able to scale and trust me I
know it might sound basic and it might
sound boring but without the risk
management this is not possible once I
understood the importance of it my
trading completely changed forever and
this is honestly the most powerful
concept that led me from level five to
level 100 in a matter of 3 months so I'm
going to share with you in this video
the concept of risk management how I use
it and how you guys can learn it from it
and then use it so you guys can scale
your trading and for the first thing you
need to understand what is risk
management what is it why is it so
important and why is it necessary right
I can't just take a trade on the market
risk whatever I want and see what
happens no that's not how this works
same way how a business has a a certain
percentage that it allocates to
marketing a certain percentage that it
allocates to employees certain
percentage that it allocates to savings
it's kind of the same thing but with
trading except you don't have to divide
it into all these different factors you
just use risk management for a trade and
that's it you can't have random
percentage everywhere so what is risk
management it's literally what it is
you're risk managing your account so you
need to know that the money that you put
into your trading account that is your
account balance and based off of your
account balance you can't risk the whole
entire account balance that defeats the
purpose of it
if you want to bet $100 per trade don't
just deposit 100 bucks and risk the full
hundred bucks cuz then you lose it then
you have to deposit again you deposit
what you're willing to invest into the
market so let's say $11,000 and if
you're willing to risk $100 now you're
only risking 10% of the actual account
this way if you lose a trade you still
have a margin left in the account and
it's healthy for your account versus
risking 100% of it versus 10% of it so
risk management is you're literally
managing the risk of the account balance
that you have deposited into your
trading account now you might be asking
why is risk management important and I'm
here to tell you right now without risk
management it's not going to work
impossible it's not going to work it's
like a business if a business doesn't
have a certain percentage allocated for
marketing a certain percentage allocated
for savings the business will go under
because the financials aren't in order
same thing in trading you can't just
risk one day 500 bucks you can't risk
another day $1,000 that's not the risk
manager you have to have a strict risk
management rule that every single time
you take a trade you risk the same
percentage per trade so when you have
your p&l chart and let's say you want to
present it to an investor so you can
showcase your skill set so you can
allocate more funds so that way you can
manage more money and then that's how
you scale your trading they need to see
a consistent risk management on their
account nobody wants to give you money
to trade if they can't see that you're
consistently respecting it and risking
the same amount and making the same
amount they don't want to see their p&l
go up and down and their money just
fluctuate out of the BL so now that you
understand that I want to let you you
know the main mistakes that the Traders
make with risk management and it drives
me crazy because if I would have learned
this at the beginning of my journey I
would have saved myself I think about a
year and a half into my journey so the
first point is risk management is
percentage based system not dollar based
system so let me explain so when you're
going to go take a trade don't base it
off money base it off of percentage so
what does that mean so earlier to the
example that I gave to you guys earlier
if you have $11,000 in an account don't
think of it oh I want to make $500 with
the $1,000 cuz when you look at it in a
percentage based system you have just
made 50% of your account and a lot of
people want to do that every single day
every single other day once a week once
a month and think about that for a
second 50% a day 50% a week 50% a month
those are all unrealistic numbers it's
not going to happen now the opportunity
is there for you to be able to do that
but it's not something sustainable it's
not something that you could do monthin
and month out every single month so risk
management is a percentage based system
so now you tell me okay I want to make
anywhere from 8 to 10% a month I'm like
you know what that is a fact anybody can
do that it's something accessible and
consistent now I know 8 to 10% a month
doesn't seem like a lot of money on
$1,000 right that's about 80 to 100
bucks which is okay but now take that
same 8 to 10% on 100K account 200k
account 300K account and so on and so
forth now the numbers have change now
you can be making on 100K account
anywhere from $8 to $10,000 a month you
can leave your job and you can trade
full-time so you see how now the same
percentage based system works but on
bigger accounts and that is where it's
meant to work on bigger accounts let's
be honest guys we're in the financial
Market we're here to make money you
can't really do a big impact with $1,000
in the market you have to either get
funded or allocate a lot of funds and
that's where I got literally all of My
Success with funding companies because I
got funded 100K and I made about 27 to
28% in a single month and I got my
$28,000 payout but over the course of
about 39 days I made 28% on 100K account
now I would have not made that same
$28,000 from $1,000 account it's not
realistic so the biggest mistake that
people make with risk management is
thinking that it's about money it's not
about money guys it is about percentage
that once you take that percentage and
you put it on an account size then that
equals to money so when you're going to
go take your next trade think about how
much percentage am I going to risk not
about how much money am I going to risk
so now you may be asking yourself should
risk management always be applied in the
same way and to be honest the answer is
depending your objective what are you
trying to do are you on a personal
account are you on a funded account are
you on a side account that you don't
really care about so I'm going to set
you three different examples on
different risk management approach that
you should do depending on the approach
you should have so the first risk
management approach is the conservative
approach where it's risking anywhere
from 0.5 to 1% per trade now I know this
might seem like a little bit but again
keep in mind big numbers keep in mind
$100,000 $200,000 which realistically it
is extremely accessible to anybody out
there as soon as you have the skill set
so you risk anywhere from 0.5 to 1%
every single trade and this is what I
personally recommend to Traders taking
trades on the lower time frame simply
because you're getting in and out of the
market more frequently so you can see
yourself taking more amount of Trades
and you don't want to be taking a lot of
trades on high risk so this is where you
lower your risk but you can take more
trades where then inevitably it can make
you more money so the conservative
approach is meant for lower time frame
traders that are executing more trades
either one to three trades a day or even
one to three trades a session my second
point is my recommended risk management
which is simply what it's an industry
standard I'd say which is anywh from
risking 1 to 2% per trade now the key to
this is once you pick the percentage you
stick to it you don't go up or down when
you're making money or you're losing
money for example let's say you are
decide to risk 1% and then you take five
wins in a row with a one to two risk
reward you have now made about 10% now
you feel like you're the king of the
world and now you want to up your risk
to 2% and at the moment that you up your
risk 2%
you lose two trades let's say now it
took you five trades to make 10% and
with two trades you have simply knocked
down 40% of that work versus if you
would have stuck to risking 1% you would
have only lost 20% of that so you'd
still be up 8% versus only being up 60%
and this is key because my recommended
risk management is 1 to 2% and whatever
percentage you choose you stick to it
and you do not move Mo it for anything
until the end of the month which I'm
going to explain a little bit more on
that which is my personal risk
management which is the next Topic in
this video but recommended risk
management is anywhere from 1 to 2% and
then last is obviously the riskier risk
management or what I like to call it you
the generates right a lot of you guys
out there like flipping the accounts a
lot of you guys out there like taking
the high risk and it's okay I do it all
the time on my personal account or side
account that I don't really care for and
it can be anywhere from 3 to 5% of your
account and even then that's still not
enough for for some of you guys but
think about it if you risk 5% of your
account and then you get a 1 to3 risk
reward ratio you have just made 15% on
one trade that's more percentage than
any Bank out there makes a year and
you're literally making that on one
single trade which can play out in one
single day so the riskier approach I
recommend is done on a personal account
so that way you don't breach any rules
on a funded account or it should then
get done on a small flipping account
that you really don't care for and these
three different types of risk management
approaches is what I do myself the
conservative approach I really don't do
as much anymore because I feel very
confident with my set and foret strategy
I've been profitable now for about 6
years and my students are getting
results every single day and when you
predict the markets for about 5 years
you get more confidence so you could you
know you're willing to risk more I'm
more in between the recommended and the
risky side of the risk management and
let me explain to you how I do it at the
beginning of every single month I risk a
percentage that I'm going to to choose
for the month so let's say I'm going to
risk 3% I risk 3% for the whole entire
month and I stick to it doesn't matter
if I lose five trades in a row doesn't
matter if I win 20 trades in a row it
does not matter I use the same exact
risk management for the whole entire
month that way the p&l at the end of the
month I have a stat I don't have a
fluctuated risk management approach cuz
I can literally risk 3% on month one and
on month two risk 1% and win and lose
the same amount of times but I have the
same risk Ro ratio so the p&l chart
balances out it's a little bit more
complicated I can make a video on that
as well but it makes sense to the
investors and I only risk 3 to 5% on
certain months out of the Year and that
is November December January and
February and maybe March those are the
months statistically that I've seen in
my trading that I have the best results
and that is where I decide to risk a
little bit more versus is not because we
all know during the summer which comes
August June July markets are a little
bit slower and I want to make a lot of
money at the beginning of the year so
when it comes to summer I don't have to
take a trade and I can have lower risk
management and it not bother me because
I might killed it at the beginning of
the year and this is something that has
taken me about 5 and a half years to
kind of figure out and the information
that I've given you in this video is
honestly enough to change your trading
completely if you use it the right way
or to be honest to at least stop losing
money because the goal goal as a
beginner Trader is not to make money
right away it's to stop losing money 99%
of Traders lose money and if you could
be that 1% that doesn't lose money
you're destined to succeed because if
you can figure out how to not lose money
I can guarantee you can figure out how
to now make money and the best way to
achieve how to make money you need to
have a winning strategy profitable
strategy that can lead you to that
success and if you want to learn the
same strategy that I use every single
week that I get on a call with my
students that leads hundreds of them to
make anywhere from ,000 to $1,500
a week as a beginner set and forget
Trader just click the link in the
description below there's a video there
that explains to you what 5 and a half
years of trading led me to and how I
figured out the secret formula of a
profitable Trader and how now students
in the first 3 months of using the set
forget strategy they make anywhere from
,000 to $1,500 a week using the set and
forget strategy so if you want to know
more about it the link in the
description below I hope this video was
very useful for you guys and you guys
are able to now take this risk
management approach and stop losing
money and now you guys can apply a
profitable strategy like set don't
forget and you guys can now start making
money and become a profitable Trader so
appreciate you guys watching all the
vide to the end I'll see you guys in the
next video